<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>editorX &#8211; CSA: Cyber Security Association @ BYU-Idaho</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 18:03:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../../assets/images/cropped-icon-greensquare-32x32.png</url>
	<title>editorX &#8211; CSA: Cyber Security Association @ BYU-Idaho</title>
	<link>./../../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Join Us (Spring 2021)!</title>
		<link>./../../../join-us/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[editorX]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 18:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=775</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you curious? Do you like scavenger hunts, escape rooms, or other problem solving games? Do you have grit? If so, the come join BYU-I&#8217;s Cyber Security Association (CSA)! Why [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="692" height="384" src="./../../../../assets/images/img-join.png" alt="" class="wp-image-776" srcset="./../../../../assets/images/img-join.png 692w, ./../../../../assets/images/img-join-300x166.png 300w, ./../../../../assets/images/img-join-150x83.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 692px) 100vw, 692px" /></figure>



<p>Are you curious?  Do you like scavenger hunts, escape rooms, or other problem solving games?  Do you have grit?<br><br>If so, the come join BYU-I&#8217;s Cyber Security Association (CSA)!   <br><br>Why join?</p>



<ul><li>Meet new people with common interests</li><li>Explore potential jobs in cyber security?</li><li>Learn some computer &#8220;hacking&#8221; skills</li><li>Learn to better solve problems</li><li>Be part of a team</li><li>Have fun in friendly games and competitions</li><li>Start your path from zero to cyber hero</li><li>4 Membership options to fit you needs</li><li>We want you!</li></ul>



<h3><br><a href="http://www.byuicsa.org/join"><strong>www.byuicsa.org/join</strong></a></h3>



<p>Not quite sure if you want to join?  Sign up as a &#8220;Friend of CSA&#8221; to stay informed of upcoming meetings and try us out.<a href="./../../../../membership/index.html"> <strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">It&#8217;s FREE!</span></strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Big Tesla Hack</title>
		<link>./../../../the-big-tesla-hack/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[editorX]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 06:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=1149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Big Tesla Hack: A hacker gained control over the entire fleet, but fortunately he’s a good guy]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h5>CSA Editors note:</h5>
<p>This article shows the advantage of learning to &#8220;hack&#8221;.  It is part of a bug bounty program from Tesla.  The goal of these &#8220;white hat hackers&#8221; (ethical &#8211; good guy hackers) is to find weaknesses in systems before the black hat hackers (bad guys) do.   This way the weaknesses can be strengthened and people and companies are safer.</p>
<h3><a href="https://electrek.co/2020/08/27/tesla-hack-control-over-entire-fleet/">The Big Tesla Hack: A hacker gained control over the entire fleet, but fortunately he’s a good guy</a></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1150 size-full" src="./../../../../assets/images/news_bugBounty_Tesl.jpg" alt="" width="692" height="384" srcset="./../../../../assets/images/news_bugBounty_Tesl.jpg 692w, ./../../../../assets/images/news_bugBounty_Tesl-300x166.jpg 300w, ./../../../../assets/images/news_bugBounty_Tesl-150x83.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 692px) 100vw, 692px" />A few years ago, a hacker managed to exploit vulnerabilities in Tesla’s servers to gain access and control over the automaker’s entire fleet.</p>
<p>He was an early member of the Tesla “root access” community, a group of Tesla owners who would hack their own cars to get more control over them and even unlock unreleased features.</p>
<p>At the time, Hughes was using his knowledge to tinker with salvaged Tesla vehicles and build off-grid energy storage systems and electric conversion kits.</p>
<p>He turned the hobby into a business selling Tesla parts from salvaged vehicles and building his own controllers to help people make cool projects out of those parts.</p>
<p>He told Electrek:</p>
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>“I found a hole in the server-side of that mechanism that allowed me to basically get data for every Supercharger worldwide about once every few minutes.”</p></blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft wp-image-1151" src="./../../../../assets/images/news-tesla01-137x300.jpg" alt="" width="274" height="600" srcset="./../../../../assets/images/news-tesla01-137x300.jpg 137w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-tesla01-468x1024.jpg 468w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-tesla01-69x150.jpg 69w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-tesla01-768x1681.jpg 768w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-tesla01-702x1536.jpg 702w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-tesla01.jpg 846w" sizes="(max-width: 274px) 100vw, 274px" />The hacker shared the data on the Tesla Motors Club forum, and the automaker seemingly wasn’t happy about it.</p>
<p>The practice, known as whitehat hacking, wasn’t his main focus, but like most tech companies, Tesla has a bug reporting system in place to reward people who find and report vulnerabilities.</p>
<p>It’s at that point that Hughes decided to compile a bug report (today he released an annotated version of<a href="https://t.co/zcEkZyq7Mq?amp=1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"> the report</a>). Since he was already recently in contact with Tesla’s head of software security, who was Aaron Sigel at the time, he decided to email him directly with his finding.</p>
<p>This was a big deal.</p>
<p>Within minutes of receiving that email on that Friday afternoon in March of 2017, Sigel called Hughes.</p>
<p>Now back then, Tesla’s autonomous capabilities were much more limited than the driver-assist features found in Tesla’s Autopilot and Full Self-Driving packages now.</p>
<h2>Tesla Cybersecurity Today</h2>
<p>The good news is that Tesla has since significantly increased its effort to secure its network and overall cybersecurity.</p>
<p>The automaker <a href="https://bugcrowd.com/tesla" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)">increased its max payout per reported bug</a> to $15,000 in 2018, and it has ramped up its security team as well as its relationship with hackers through participation in hacking conferences.</p>
<p>Over the last few years, Tesla has brought its cars as targets in the popular <a href="https://electrek.co/2020/01/10/tesla-hacking-challenge/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)">Pwn2Own hacking competition</a>.</p>
<p>David Lau, vice president of vehicle software at Tesla, recently commented on the effort:</p>
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>We develop our cars with the highest standards of safety in every respect, and our work with the security research community is invaluable to us. Since launching our bug bounty program in 2014 — the first to include a connected consumer vehicle — we have continuously increased our investments into partnerships with security researchers to ensure that all Tesla owners constantly benefit from the brightest minds in the community. We look forward to learning about, and rewarding, great work in Pwn2Own so that we can continue to improve our products and our approach to designing inherently secure systems.</p></blockquote>
<p>Also, Tesla owners will supposedly soon get two-factor authentication for their Tesla account.</p>
<p><a href="https://electrek.co/2020/08/27/tesla-hack-control-over-entire-fleet"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Continue reading &#8230;.</strong></span></a></p>
<p><strong>Source:</strong> <a href="https://electrek.co/2020/08/27/tesla-hack-control-over-entire-fleet">https://electrek.co/2020/08/27/tesla-hack-control-over-entire-fleet</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Virtual Career Fair 2020 &#8211; Cyber Security &#8211; (Post Event Update)</title>
		<link>./../../../virtual-career-fair-2020-cyber-security-sept-4/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[editorX]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 05:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=587</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Update: 9/5/2020 If you are looking to work for a large company like Walmart, IBM AAA Automotive, Raytheon, SAIC, Disney or Verizon, then this is a great way to make [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Update: 9/5/2020</p>
<p>If you are looking to work for a large company like Walmart, IBM AAA Automotive, Raytheon, SAIC, Disney or Verizon, then this is a great way to make contacts and meet job hunters looking for new talent.&nbsp; If working for a government agency such as US Army, one of the 8 National Laboratories, FEMA, CISA, DIA/DOD, Department of Commerce, or even the NSA (National Security Agency), then attending the Virtual Career Fair 2021 may be great for you.&nbsp; This event only happens annually, but these employers are constantly looking for new talent both as full time and as internships.</p>
<p>The event had 2 live video key notes speakers, a virtual exhibit hall,booths with interactive chat, contact information, pdfs, and LinkedIn profiles for key people. <img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1162" src="./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair2-1024x543.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="543" srcset="./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair2-1024x543.jpg 1024w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair2-300x159.jpg 300w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair2-150x80.jpg 150w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair2-768x407.jpg 768w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair2-1536x814.jpg 1536w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair2.jpg 1677w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1161" src="./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair-1024x566.png" alt="" width="600" height="331" srcset="./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair-1024x566.png 1024w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair-300x166.png 300w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair-150x83.png 150w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair-768x424.png 768w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair-1536x848.png 1536w, ./../../../../assets/images/news-CyberFair.png 1693w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /></p>
<hr>
<p><strong><em>The&nbsp;Centers of Academic Excellence (CAE) in Cybersecurity Community is hosting the fourth&nbsp;annual CAE Virtual Career Fair (VCF), sponsored by the&nbsp;<a href="https://ncyte.net/">National Cybersecurity Training and Education (NCyTE) Center&nbsp;</a>and the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nsf.gov/">National Science Foundation (NSF)</a><a href="https://www.nsf.gov/">,</a>&nbsp;on September 4, 2020, from 9:00 am-1:00 pm PT.&nbsp;</em></strong>Our virtual career fair is unique in that we invite students/alumni from 300+ institutions designated as CAEs in Research (CAE-R), Cyber Defense Education (CAE-CDE), and Cyber Operations (CAE-CO)&nbsp;to participate. Institutions receive the CAE in Cybersecurity designation after meeting the rigorous requirements of the program set forth by the National Security Agency (NSA) and the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). The standards set forth by the NSA/DHS curriculum guidelines also ensure students from CAE institutions receive a quality cybersecurity education that prepares them for a career in the cyber workforce.</p>
<p>As the CAE in Cybersecurity program continues to designate new CAEs, the number of students participating in the CAE VCF grows each year.&nbsp;<em><strong>Last year, 1200+ students/alumni participated in the CAE VCF.&nbsp;This year, the community has an estimated 10,000+ students graduating from junior colleges and universities seeking jobs in cybersecurity. In addition, our community has an estimated 20,000+ students that are eligible for internships in the 2020-2021 academic year.</strong></em>&nbsp;Students/alumni from CAE designated institutions are extremely valuable to any organization as they must meet the rigorous curriculum requirements set forth by the NSA/DHS to graduate.</p>
<p>Survey data from the 2019&nbsp;event indicate both employers and students positively receive the CAE VCF. Many students find careers through the VCF,&nbsp;and many of the same employers return each year&nbsp;to participate.</p>
<p>Click here for more information: <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><em><a href="https://www.caecommunity.org/news/cae-virtual-career-fair-2020">CAE Virtual Career Fair 2020 | CAE in Cybersecurity Community</a></em></span></p>
<p><em>&nbsp;</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pen Testers Who Got Arrested Doing Their Jobs Tell All</title>
		<link>./../../../pen-testers-who-got-arrested-doing-their-jobs-tell-all/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[editorX]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Coalfire&#8217;s Gary De Mercurio and Justin Wynn share the details of their physical penetration-testing engagement gone wrong, as well as recommendations for protecting all red teamers. When they first scanned [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone  wp-image-600" src="./../../../../assets/images/image0-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="547" height="308" srcset="./../../../../assets/images/image0-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../../assets/images/image0-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../../assets/images/image0-150x84.jpg 150w, ./../../../../assets/images/image0-768x432.jpg 768w, ./../../../../assets/images/image0-1536x864.jpg 1536w, ./../../../../assets/images/image0-2048x1152.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 547px) 100vw, 547px" /></p>
<p>Coalfire&#8217;s Gary De Mercurio and Justin Wynn share the details of their physical penetration-testing engagement gone wrong, as well as recommendations for protecting all red teamers.</p>
<p class="">When they first scanned the cardkey to the front entrance of the Dallas County Courthouse in Iowa, red-team experts Gary De Mercurio and Justin Wynn didn&#8217;t hear the requisite click of a lock disengaging. It was after midnight on Sept. 11, 2019, the last leg of their penetration-testing engagement for the state of Iowa&#8217;s Judicial Branch, and they got their first big surprise of that&nbsp;<a href="https://www.darkreading.com/attacks-breaches/coalfire-ceo-wants-criminal-charges-against-his-employees-dropped/d/d-id/1336232" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">now-infamous evening</a>.</p>
<p>&#8220;Justin grabs the door and we look at each other, and I said, &#8216;Did it work?&#8217; and he&#8217;s like, &#8216;No, it&#8217;s open,'&#8221; recalls De Mercurio, a senior manager at Coalfire. &#8220;The door was locked, but they hadn&#8217;t latched it all the way.&#8221;</p>
<p>So the two social engineering and physical pen-test experts could get a more accurate take on the entrance security, Wynn closed the door and they started all over again with the cardkey, this time with the door locked. De Mercurio then slid a plastic cutting board retrofitted with a handy notch into the doorjamb and used it to unlatch the door. The pair figured they had somewhere between 20 to 30 seconds from then until the building alarm would sound, so they executed the usual next step in the physical testing process: checking the strength of the alarm&#8217;s passcode settings by first typing in the system&#8217;s default code as well as easy-to-guess combinations.</p>
<p>Once the alarm sounded, the pair went back to work looking for other potential vulnerabilities in the courthouse while waiting to see if the authorities would respond. &#8230; Read the full story here: &nbsp;<em><a href="https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities---threats/pen-testers-who-got-arrested-doing-their-jobs-tell-all/d/d-id/1338570">Pen Testers Who Got Arrested Doing Their Jobs Tell All</a></em></p>
<p><em><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone" src="./../../../../assets/images/dr-logo-1.jpg" alt="" width="136" height="136"><br />
</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Password cracking with the Cyber Security Association</title>
		<link>./../../../password-cracking-with-the-cyber-security-association/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[editorX]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 05:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=513</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Published by&#160;&#160;Holly Dorman&#160; Fingers tap-tap-tapped across keyboards. The team spoke in hushed voices as they worked to crack the password. The light from the projector and individual computer screens lit [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="768" class="wp-image-252" style="width: 600px;" src="./../../../../assets/images/CSA-Meeting-scaled-1.jpg" alt="" srcset="./../../../../assets/images/CSA-Meeting-scaled-1.jpg 1024w, ./../../../../assets/images/CSA-Meeting-scaled-1-300x225.jpg 300w, ./../../../../assets/images/CSA-Meeting-scaled-1-150x113.jpg 150w, ./../../../../assets/images/CSA-Meeting-scaled-1-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><br>Published by&nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="https://byuiscroll.org/author/holly-dorman/">Holly Dorman</a>&nbsp;<br><br><br>Fingers tap-tap-tapped across keyboards. The team spoke in hushed voices as they worked to crack the password.</p>



<p>The light from the projector and individual computer screens lit up the room, casting shadows across faces.</p>



<p>The BYU-Idaho Cyber Security Association teaches students of all skill levels about the different tools and techniques used in cybersecurity through hands-on experience. Student instructors taught participants how to crack passwords at their meeting on Feb. 13.</p>



<p>“When I came to college, I knew I wanted to do something with computers,” said Justin Wilson, a junior studying computer information technology&nbsp;and CSA president. “Cybersecurity is something that has always fascinated me … I’d read stories in the news and stuff about things that were going on in cybersecurity, but I never really saw myself in the middle of that … Being in CSA has helped me come to realize that cybersecurity is what I want to do for a career.”</p>



<p>CSA participates in different competitions across the country, the next one being the Pacific Rim Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition. Competitions like PRCCDC provide opportunities for students, including jobs, internships and the chance to have fun. More information about PRCCDC can be found on&nbsp;<a href="http://prccdc.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">their website</a>.</p>



<p>“Three years ago, we started to get more regularly engaged in competitions,” said Kory Godfrey, computer information technology department chair. “Competitions are sometimes described as ‘the bridge between an academic environment and the day-to-day everyday workplace.&#8217;”</p>



<p>Potential employers also notice the extra effort to hone students’ skills.</p>



<p>“We’ve had students put this on their resume and it really seems to set them apart from other job-seekers,” said Carl Gibbons, Computer Information Technology faculty member and advisor for CSA.</p>



<p>Wilson hopes the idea of learning new skills will entice others to come and join CSA.</p>



<p>“It doesn’t matter how much you know or how little you know,” Wilson said. “Just come. Just be here and learn.”<br><br>Source: <a href="https://byuiscroll.org/password-cracking-with-the-cyber-security-association/">https://byuiscroll.org/password-cracking-with-the-cyber-security-association/</a></p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BYU Idaho Student becomes SANS Finalist</title>
		<link>./../../../byu-idaho-student-becomes-sans-finalist/index.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[editorX]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 05:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../../index.html?p=510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Justin Wilson of BYU-Idaho&#8217;s Cyber Security Association becomes one of the 100 Finalist to earn a SANS Scholarship worth over $22,000.&#160; Justin beat out over 13,000 other university students to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-291" src="./../../../../assets/images/logo-cyberfast2.png" alt="" width="687" height="332" srcset="./../../../../assets/images/logo-cyberfast2.png 687w, ./../../../../assets/images/logo-cyberfast2-300x145.png 300w, ./../../../../assets/images/logo-cyberfast2-150x72.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 687px) 100vw, 687px" /><br />
Justin Wilson of BYU-Idaho&#8217;s Cyber Security Association becomes one of the 100 Finalist to earn a SANS Scholarship worth over $22,000.&nbsp; Justin beat out over 13,000 other university students to win the 2019 Challenge.</p>
<blockquote><p>Cyber FastTrack is happy to announce that 100 exceptional participants have made it to the finish line! Scholarships for advanced cybersecurity training have been awarded to this select group of students who competed over several months to solve more than 250 cybersecurity challenges. Congratulations to the students who made the list of Cyber FastTrack Finalists!</p></blockquote>
<p>Great job, Justin!</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.sans.org/press/announcement/2019/10/03/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.sans.org/press/announcement/2019/10/03/1</a></strong></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong><a href="https://medium.com/cyber-fasttrack/scholarships-awarded-to-100-cyber-fasttrack-finalists-287b209630" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://medium.com/cyber-fasttrack/scholarships-awarded-to-100-cyber-fasttrack-finalists-287b209630</a></strong></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
